Theodore Herzfeld

DevOps/Systems Engineer

teddy.herzfeld@icloud.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/theodore-herzfeld/ 484-577-7312 Herndon, Virginia, USA

Experienced DevOps and SRE Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in cloud and on-prem infrastructure. Skilled in AWS infrastructure, automation, and Python. Strong engineering professional with a focus on continuous integration and deployment, and infrastructure-as-code systems such as Terraform and Ansible.

Work Experience

DevOps Engineer Apr 2023 - Oct 2024

Zillow

Responsible for on-prem and cloud deployment of Real-estate agent facing applications for Showingtime, the nation's largest real-estate CRM, present in all markets across the USA, grossing \$1.95 billion in revenue company-wide.

- First responder to Cloudstrike outage, responded quickly and triaged the incident, resulting in reduction of outage time company-wide by hours.
- Authored Ansible roles for system provisioning, application deployment, and configuration, enabling automated application deployment.
- Created Packer/Teamcity/Vagrant build pipeline to create VM packages for analysts to test against, eliminating the
 requirement to build and provision test environments on the analysts' laptops, reducing required direct intervention and
 allowing self-service troubleshooting and repair.
- Enabled building and deployment of new applications in response to developer needs by creating new CI/CD pipelines and scripts.
- Wrote Dockerfiles and Kubernetes manifests in response to developer needs to facilitate build and deployment of new applications.
- Authored Terraform modules to create, provision, and manage AWS and on-prem infrastructure, implementing infrastructure
- Worked in Vsphere to create and maintain on-prem infrastructure in response to developer needs and operational incidents.

DevOps/Systems Engineer

Gannett, USA TODAY NETWORK

Feb 2022 - Feb 2023

Responsible for deployment and troubleshooting of various internal and external applications for organizations company wide, including USA Today; supporting more than 11,000 employees and millions of visitors in site traffic.

- Migrated Jenkins pipelines to Github Actions, optimizing CI/CD pipelines across a number of applications and reducing deployment times from 20-40 minutes to 30 seconds to 5 minutes.
- Created Python library and Docker container for Github Actions, allowing developers to write CI/CD pipelines directly in Python, enabling development of pipelines across various applications with a simplified library.
- Authored Helm charts, Dockerfiles, and CI/CD pipelines in response to company needs for new applications, enabling rapid deployment of new services.

Advanced Repair Agent

Feb 2018 - Feb 2022

Geek Squad

Provided front-line support and repair for public users, including hardware and software repair, and logical data recovery.

- Interpersonal communication, conflict resolution, and de-escalation
- Actively promoted from Front-desk intake and support agent to Full-service technician.
- Restored data in multiple devices using advanced data recovery techniques such as file-carving and filesystem repair.
- · Created automation scripts to connect systems to WiFi or install applications, reducing repair times
- Software and Hardware troubleshooting and problem resolution.

· Repair and replacement of damaged or malfunctioning parts.

Projects

Personal Homelab Jan 2020 - Present

Deployment and Maintenance of a homelab environment from hardware up consisting of multiple servers and service architectures.

- · Self-hosted/managed Kubernetes cluster
- Terraform wherever possible
- · Ansible server provisioning, configuration, and management
- · Hashicorp Vault secrets management
- · GitOps and CI/CD Argo, Gitlab Pipelines
- Nginx reverese proxy with LetsEncrypt certificates
- · Custom DNS Pihole, Bind, Cloudflare DOH proxying
- · Cloudflare DDoS protection
- · Fedora (RHEL) and Ubuntu servers
- Dell and SuperMicro servers (IPMI and DRAC)
- · Proxmox virtualization
- · Docker and docker-compose
- Custom Docker images
- · Cisco networking hardware
- PfSense router
- · SMB and NFS storage
- Linux raid ~54 Gib usable in XFS. 2 Raid6 arrays spanned by LVM

Core Skills

Terraform, Ansible, Kubernetes, CI/CD, Linux, Windows, Vagrant, Packer, VMware, VSphere, Github Actions, Gitlab CI/CD, Teamcity, ArgoCD, Jenkins, Programming / Scripting Languages - Python, Java, Javascript, Bash, Powershell, Golang, security, information security, security technologies, security engineering, AI, operating systems, customer support, cloud security, networking, Unix, data migration, Data Delivery, API, s3, cloud technologies, distributed system, microservices, docker, agile, Software Configuration Management, Deployment Automation, Docker Software, software development, rabbitmq, redis, .NET, IIS, TCP, load-balancing, technical documentation, amazon web services, Cloud operations, load balancer, postgresql, aws cloud, dynamodb, technical analysis, engineering design, operations processes, customer service, communications, PHP, application development, object oriented design, programming languages, relational databases, typescript, SQL, rds, program design, problem solving skills, AWS, GCP

Education

Northern Virginia Community College

Aug 2018 - Present

Associates Science Computer Science

Languages

English (fluent), Japanese (conversational)

Certificates

Amazon Web Services (AWS) Cloud Practitioner

Dec 2024

Amazon